<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<conference name="edui2018" start-date="2018-10-08" end-date="2018-10-10">
    <day date="2018-10-08">
        <event type="Keynote" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location>Jefferson Theater</location>
            <speakers>Margot Lee Shetterly and Erin White</speakers>
            <title>Fireside Chat with Margot Lee Shetterly</title>
            <description>Join us for a conversation with Margot Lee Shetterly, author of the New York Times bestseller Hidden Figures, about some of the first women and people of color to break gender and racial barriers in tech. The work of these previously unsung heroes tipped the balance in favor of the United States in WWII, the Cold War, and the Space Race.
Hidden Figures tells the true story of the black women mathematicians at NASA who helped fuel some of America's greatest achievements in space. Shetterly celebrates these unsung heroes, teasing out issues of race, gender, science, and innovation against the backdrop of WWII and the Civil Rights Era.
Shetterly will also talk about the Human Computer Project, a digital archive of the stories of NASA's African-American “Human Computers” that she founded.
The conversation will be moderated by Erin White, edUi veteran and digital librarian at Virginia Commonwealth University.
            </description>
            <keywords>Keynote</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/fireside-chat-with-margot-lee-shetterly/</link>
            <photos>
                <photo type="speaker">https://www.eduiconf.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/7/2018/03/HiddenFigures_MTI_PB_nyt-199x300.jpg</photo>
            </photos>
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Jill Stover Heinze</speakers>
            <title>Getting Your Feet Wet in Services: What UX Pros Should Know about Service Design</title>
            <description>Today's UX designers are increasingly wielding their expertise in non-digital domains. As technology pervades physical environments and stakeholders recognize the value of designing for the entire user journey, UXers have compelling opportunities to extend themselves into service design roles. In some libraries, for example, UX consults on service-related concerns like wayfinding, policies, and communications. But, what exactly are you taking on when you delve into designing for services? And how is it different from designing for digital interfaces?
Before you dive into the deep end of service design, let this session help you learn to dog paddle by considering the basic characteristics of services, as well as trends in service design and marketing. The result? You'll have a better grasp on how to make strategic choices about how and if you should dip your toes into the service side of the pool, including what new skills and techniques you'll need to be successful.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/service-design/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Amanda Chestnut and Valerie Harness</speakers>
            <title>Equitable User Access in the Face of Controversy</title>
            <description>Amanda Chestnut is in the unique position of being both an artist and an arts administrator. In this talk, she will discuss her experiences within archives held by institutions, how those archives are accessed by the public, and what happened to her when the public found out that accessing information wasn&amp;#8217;t as fair or equitable as had been assumed. The focus will be on how users outside academia access, interpret, and share information – and how institutions may not be aware of that public perception.
Valerie Harness joins to discuss how this case study of painful UX can be addressed within our organizations, while Amanda shares the barriers she's hit while attempting to champion for change. Has your institution faced a similar problem? We'd love to hear from you at the end of the session, where audience members will be welcome to share how they have overcome controversy and improved access.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/equitable-user-access/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Anne Gibson</speakers>
            <title>What Letter Are You? An Alphabet of Accessibility Issues</title>
            <description>Every one of us needs the internet to be accessible. Our needs may not surface today, but they will in the future. Do we know enough about what accessibility needs look like – beyond the stereotypes of people with disabilities that we're all too aware of? And how do we get from &amp;#8220;I know my site has problems&amp;#8221; to &amp;#8220;I know how to approach them&amp;#8221;?
This talk, based on Anne's 2014 articles “An Alphabet of Accessibility Issues” and “Reframing Accessibility for the Web,” will frame accessibility through the lens of 26 people who need accessibility considerations.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/what-letter-are-you-an-alphabet-of-accessibility-issues/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Caner Uguz</speakers>
            <title>What does your app really do?&amp;#8230;and other adventures in instrumentation</title>
            <description>Compared to the number of engineering hours spent on a product, there is significantly less time spent on product design, research, and instrumentation. But product design is not just about user interfaces. It's also about systematic methods of making strategic decisions about what to build and how to build it.
Instrumentation is a significant part of this methodology, but many of us are asking the wrong questions or collecting data that doesn&amp;#8217;t answer the questions we are interested in. In this talk, I will combine two decades of experience building online tools and six years of academic research experience to give you tips and methods about how to understand your product better and make better decisions about what to work on.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/what-does-your-app-really-do/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Jenny Slaughter and Rachel DeLauder</speakers>
            <title>Naming Stuff is Hard</title>
            <description>&amp;#8220;What&amp;#8217;s in a name? That which we call a rose by any other name would smell as sweet.&amp;#8221;
Thanks, Shakespeare. That's a great sentiment, but when we're talking about websites, it gets a little complicated.
Naming components isn't just a problem for the developers who create them; it's a cross-disciplinary challenge. From variations in how something can display to patterns that reflect design behaviors, names serve different purposes for everyone, whether you're a user experience architect, designer, developer, content creator, or the end-user. And what's really challenging is that everyone is right, in their own context.
Each discipline (usually) has some sort of logic to support what they want to call things. Developers often want to name components by structure, not by the content they might contain, in order to keep the code flexible. Designers want to name by color or style, even though what's technically a single component might just be skinned with multiple display options. And if the component names don't reflect the content they'll ultimately be used for, content creators will have a hard time choosing the right one for the job (and might come after you with pitchforks).
In each phase of design, the qualities and behaviors of a component must be interpreted by the next person in line, from wireframe to design to development to content strategy to client. Without clear communication, it ends up a protracted game of telephone, except at the end no one's laughing. A simple “circle-headshot” in one use case devolves into “circle-headshot-full-width-inset-with-green-link-style” in another, and things get complicated quickly, leading to widespread panic and confusion.
We've spent way too much time debating this subject with our (very smart, very passionate) teammates. And while we've come to realize there's no one-size-fits-all solution, we'd like to save you a few of the gray hairs we've earned along the way. We'll share hilarious missteps we wish we could take back — along with some examples of what's worked well.
Takeaways:

Understand the needs of each discipline and what the consequences of different naming conventions could mean for the project
Learn the importance of documentation and alignment starting from the very first sketch
Hear our best recommendations based on years of experience, arguments, and sometimes-heated debates

            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/naming-stuff-is-hard/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Emily Patterson and Megan Rowe</speakers>
            <title>Are Your Neglected Blogs and Social Accounts Worth Saving?</title>
            <description>You haven&amp;#8217;t updated your organization&amp;#8217;s blog or Twitter account since 2015, and they&amp;#8217;re ghost towns. You&amp;#8217;re out of content ideas. The images are outdated or the wrong size. Your numbers are near zero. What to do? In our session, we&amp;#8217;ll help you evaluate your failing accounts and decide if they&amp;#8217;re worth saving, and if so, how.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/neglected-blogs/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Vera Rhoads</speakers>
            <title>Chatbots, AR, VR, Drones&amp;#8230;Emerging ways of delivering information</title>
            <description>Explore how the information needs of the 21st century education ecosystem with all its participants are evolving and how UX can enhance these emerging experiences. This presentation is focused on the student lifecycle experience (understood broadly and through the concept of a lifelong learner) and shows examples of successful transformations with emerging technologies in engagement, new student orientation, and more.
Learn how new technologies such as chatbots, ioT, AR and VR, and drone systems are transforming the student experience. Learn some ideas from a UX and Design Thinking perspective to enhance these newer technologies and effectively integrate them into the student experience.
Hear case studies from several universities.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/chatbots-ar-vr-drones/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Panel" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Dan Cotting and Mason Brown and Susanna Klein</speakers>
            <title>Digital App Design for Academic Research</title>
            <description>Join us for a discussion on the ins and outs of designing custom digital applications for academic research. In 2017, VCUarts Department of Music Professor Susanna Klein partnered with app consultancy Shockoe to design and develop a custom application for a rigorous study on &amp;#8220;The Power of Information for Goal Oriented Processes in Music Education.&amp;#8221;
The panel will discuss how the study informed the design approach and how Shockoe&amp;#8217;s UX and UI designers helped create an assessment tool that was central to Professor Klein&amp;#8217;s study.
            </description>
            <keywords>Panel</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/digital-app-design-for-academic-research/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="12:30 pm" end-time="02:00 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>Lunch</title>
            <description></description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/lunch/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Workshop" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="05:00 pm">
            <location>City Space</location>
            <speakers>Chris Love</speakers>
            <title>Making the Progressive Web App Your Stakeholders Want</title>
            <description>Progressive web apps (PWAs) are the new hot thing everyone's talking about. These mobile-friendly websites that can do almost everything native apps can are what your next batch of incoming students are going to expect. They combine maximum reach with functionality previously reserved only for native apps.
PWAs are built with web technologies you're probably already familiar with, but as usual, things are not quite as simple as they seem.
This half-day workshop will cover what a progressive web app is and how you can update or create new PWAs utilizing common caching techniques. You will also learn about the essential requirements of a progressive web app including https, a valid web manifest, and a registered service worker.
The goal is to learn how you can leverage the traditional website architecture you&amp;#8217;re already familiar with to start building the progressive web apps your stakeholders want.
            </description>
            <keywords>Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/pwa-workshop/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Workshop" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="05:00 pm">
            <location>Live Arts - Gibson</location>
            <speakers>Amanda Costello</speakers>
            <title>Better Stakeholder Wrangling</title>
            <description>Folks who work with the web wear many hats, often including project manager. Managing and collaborating well with stakeholders is a key component to any project's success, but the politics, history, and culture of an organization give this task an extra layer of complexity not often found in PM training or books.
Drawing from more than a decade's worth of experience working with higher ed projects and egos big and small, Amanda will get you equipped to roll with whatever stakeholders may throw at you. This workshop will be helpful if you are working within a complicated org chart, or if you are struggling with the internal politics of juggling differing priorities.
            </description>
            <keywords>Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/better-stakeholder-wrangling/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Workshop" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="05:00 pm">
            <location>Old Metropolitan</location>
            <speakers>Jimmy Chandler</speakers>
            <title>Design Sprints for Learning</title>
            <description>One of the hottest techniques in UX today is the 5-day design sprint, used to answer “critical business questions through design, prototyping, and testing ideas with customers.” Sprints can help launch a startup, assist existing organizations work through difficult problems, or be useful to anyone with an idea worth exploring.
But design sprints don't have to be 5 days — they can be done in as little as a few hours and still be a valuable tool for learning, as you&amp;#8217;ll see in this workshop.
You&amp;#8217;ll learn all about design sprints by doing condensed versions of several activities that are core to the experience. This will be mixed with short presentations on the basics of how to facilitate a successful sprint, and how organizations can incorporate them for educational purposes. So, you&amp;#8217;ll both learn by doing and be able to absorb the presentations in easily digestible chunks.
The activities will all be conducted around a specific case study from the .edu space. You&amp;#8217;ll be given a full scenario and enough background material to be successful.
We'll cover the basics of a design sprint, tips and tricks for success, and get into specifics on how it can also be used to facilitate learning in a formal education setting, or within any team.
You&amp;#8217;ll leave the workshop with the slide deck, a guide to conducting design sprints, resources for further reading on the topic, and the confidence to incorporate design sprints into your work.
            </description>
            <keywords>Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/design-sprints-for-learning/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="06:00 pm" end-time="09:00 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>Opening Night Reception</title>
            <description></description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/opening-night-reception/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
    </day>
    <day date="2018-10-09">
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Whitney Quesenbery</speakers>
            <title>Storytelling: Finding the insights in research data</title>
            <description>Understanding our users starts from user research. But the complexities of the user patterns, behaviors, perceptions, and motivations can be hard to communicate in ways that help the team really understand the mindset of their audience.
Stories let us shape research data into compelling narratives that build empathy and engage teams in the user journey and see both research insights and problems user experience through the eyes of your users.
Whitney will show you how to use stories to explore the moments that shape the experience, so you can use those insights to design for people with their own interests, habits and goals.
You'll learn how to:

Use stories as a research analysis tool
Ask the right questions during user research to elicit insights
Show the experience through the eyes of your customers

            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/storytelling-finding-the-insights-in-research-data/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Aaron Knight and Nikki Massaro Kauffman</speakers>
            <title>Accessible Wayfinding: It's Not Uncharted Territory</title>
            <description>How do you make content that is inherently visually accessible? There are a multitude of ways you can help your wayfinding and other visual content to be more accessible for all of your visitors. After all, they need to be able to find you, too.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/accessible-wayfinding/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Jonathan Bradley</speakers>
            <title>I Reject this Reality and Substitute a Virtual One: How to Build A VR Service in Your Library (or Other Space)</title>
            <description>Join the creator of the Virtual Environments Studio at Virginia Tech&amp;#8217;s University Libraries for a breakdown of everything you might need to know about building a Virtual Reality or Augmented Reality service for your university. This talk will address the logistics of building and offering the service, how the service is used to support faculty and students, and why such services have a high return on investment in terms of engagement with your community.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/library-vr-service/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Garrett Bingaman and Ryan Farrell</speakers>
            <title>Let your audience do the work: Capitalizing on user-generated content (for higher ed)</title>
            <description>Understanding your audience is key to a successful creative strategy. Why not take advantage of this and make them “secretly” work for you? Learn how our team at Purdue University benefited from past mistakes and successes and launched a successful university-wide social media photo campaign, Picture Your Purdue. By getting our audience involved, we capitalized on free content and merged it with a full redesign of the university homepage.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/user-generated-content/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Joe Sokohl</speakers>
            <title>Everything You Know Is Wrong! Design Epistemology and You</title>
            <description>How do we know what we know about our users? We have volumes espousing techniques for interviewing users, for observing the user experience, and for understanding that users are always right. We have books and articles and hours of video from conferences that show us how to do user research. We even hear why we should research users.
What we are missing, though, is the theoretical (dare I say philosophic) underpinning.
This talk looks at epistemology as it relates to users and what they do&amp;#8230;so that we can know more clearly why we&amp;#8217;re doing what we&amp;#8217;re doing.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/everything-you-know-is-wrong-toward-a-design-epistemology/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Brian Rimel and Matt Clark</speakers>
            <title>Leveraging Open Data for Deeper Insights</title>
            <description>Conceptually, open data seems simple. Publicizing your existing data encourages greater transparency, accountability, and innovation with minimal effort. Realistically, one must consider the risk versus the rewards.
Our session will explore key considerations for leveraging your existing data in conjunction with third-party content in order to extract valuable insights. Presenting real-world use cases from the Open Science Framework for publishing open research, we will walk you through combining multiple data sources in order to enrich the data. Finally, we'll explore methods of interpretation of the data through analysis and visualization.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/leveraging-open-data/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Chad Haefele</speakers>
            <title>Enhancing (and benefiting from) your buildings&amp;#8217; data in Google My Business</title>
            <description>We all manage our websites, social media accounts, and other official online presences. But what about our presence inside Google search results&amp;#8217; Knowledge Panel? It&amp;#8217;s not just SEO – Google&amp;#8217;s Business Profiles can drive a ton of traffic.
In the last year, users interacted more than 55,000 times with UNC Libraries&amp;#8217; Google Business Profiles. These profiles appear in the right column of Google results when somebody searches for a building&amp;#8217;s name. From there, users called us, got directions, and visited our websites.
Google builds these profiles automatically, with varying degrees of accuracy. But you can improve them! And once claimed, these profiles are a great way to market your events and services. We&amp;#8217;ve spent some time cleaning up our listings and exploring the possibilities. This talk will cover what we&amp;#8217;ve learned, how users are interacting with our profiles, and provide practical tips.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/building-data-google/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Claire Payne and Sarah Arnold</speakers>
            <title>How to Handle a Whole Lot of Content: A Case Study of What We've Learned</title>
            <description>With 200+ content creators, the UNC Chapel Hill Libraries website continues to grow each year. Our contributors have busy academic schedules with many user-driven responsibilities, and not everyone is an expert in producing well-organized and effectual content that appeals to a variety of users.
To curb the content bloat, our two-person content management team organizes an annual audit of our 475+ page WordPress site and 500+ LibGuides. We refined our content audit approach through 2016, 2017, and 2018, over which time we also began programmatic monthly and weekly upkeep to continually improve the experience we provide to our users.
This session will provide a case study of how a small team can effectively maintain a large amount of content in a busy academic library environment. We will share our strategies for encouraging page and guide owners to think more deeply about their content and offer tips on how we've effectively scaled our management practices to the size of our site.
Though this session focuses on WordPress and LibGuides, the techniques suggested are applicable to any CMS.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/a-whole-lot-of-content/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Keynote" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location>Jefferson Theater</location>
            <speakers>Jeremy Keith</speakers>
            <title>The Way of the Web</title>
            <description>Do you ever get overwhelmed by the ever-changing nature of web design and development? Exhausting, isn&amp;#8217;t it? How are you supposed to know which technologies and tools you should invest your time in? Will they stick around or will you just have to relearn everything in another few months?
Join Jeremy Keith as he takes a tour of the past, present, and future of working on the web. From the building blocks of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript through to frameworks and libraries right up to the latest and greatest Progressive Web Apps, this talk will examine our collective assumptions with a critical eye. By learning from the past, we can make sensible design decisions today to build the web of tomorrow.
            </description>
            <keywords>Keynote</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/the-way-of-the-web/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="12:30 pm" end-time="02:00 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>Lunch on Your Own</title>
            <description></description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/lunch-2/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Mini-Workshop" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="02:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Matt Gaskey</speakers>
            <title>Get More From Your Analytics By Applying an Ecommerce Model to Higher Ed</title>
            <description>Mini-Workshop: Part 1 of 2
If you've looked at your Google Analytics dashboard, you've probably noticed a set of Ecommerce reports. If you then shrugged them off saying “We're in Higher Ed, not Ecommerce,” think again. You're missing out on a goldmine of analytics data. Learn how to apply Ecommerce tools to your higher ed site to get so much more out of Google Analytics.
Google Analytics isn't built for higher ed. That may sound harsh, but Google Analytics is, in all fairness, biased towards the Ecommerce sector. Out-of-the-box GA is sufficient to track pageviews, measure site traffic, and define goal conversions, but what about all the on-site content you work so hard to produce? Wouldn't it be useful to know what content is driving conversions?
The answer: Apply an Ecommerce approach to higher ed. Modeling your data collection as if your site were an online store will allow you to unlock the true power of Google Analytics. Want to know which pages are driving users towards goal conversions? It's as simple as assigning a value to your goals.
Just because certain aspects of Google Analytics have ‘Ecommerce' in the name doesn't mean that we can't exploit them in Higher Ed. We just have to do a bit of mental gymnastics and the plugin will bend to our collective will. Tapping into to the Ecommerce plugin means treating our business goals as products for sale. Have an event registration form? That's a product that users buy! Have a request for info? That's a product users buy!  Have an application? That's the Taj Mahal of products your users can buy!
With enhanced Ecommerce, goal conversions are no longer individual points at the end of a series, but a progression of events that can be tied to one another.
Here are just a few examples of reporting you can set up:

Product Detail to Purchase (Program Page view to Application Submission)
Product List to Purchase (Majors/Minors list to Application Submission)
Cart to Purchase (Application Starts to Application Submission)
Promotions (Special Event Views)

Not only do we gain a set of valuable reports, but we can also add multiple layers of data into every conversion on the site.
Don't ignore the Ecommerce tools in Google Analytics. Learn how to harness them.
            </description>
            <keywords>Mini-Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/get-more-from-your-analytics-by-applying-an-ecommerce-model-to-higher-ed/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="02:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Madeline Grdina</speakers>
            <title>Distrust in the Time of Facebook</title>
            <description>Distrust for technology isn't just Facebook's problem. When users have terrible experiences with complex software or fake emails, these deep emotional issues can become a university's problem as well.
Indiana University's UX Office has confronted trust issues on both sides of the spectrum. When we started revamping a budgeting app for IU researchers, we discovered that many users simply did not trust its data. But in an unrelated security project, we saw that people were too trusting with simple systems (like email), making themselves and IU vulnerable to phishing attacks.
So how can we craft better, more trustworthy experiences?
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/distrust-in-the-time-of-facebook/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Mini-Workshop" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="02:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Andrew Boyd and Justin Schroeder</speakers>
            <title>Off With Their Heads!</title>
            <description>Part 1 of 2
It&amp;#8217;s time to decapitate your CMS and go headless. The benefits of decoupling a site&amp;#8217;s presentation (or &amp;#8220;head&amp;#8221;) from its content management are dramatic: faster load times, cleaner content types, better security, and the opportunity to create stunning user interfaces. While more and more organizations want to condemn their CMS to the guillotine, they&amp;#8217;re often unsure of how to begin.
In this hands-on mini-workshop, we&amp;#8217;ll discuss the benefits of a headless architecture, review a showcase of great live headless sites, and crack open our laptops and sharpen our blades for surgery. Attendees will have the opportunity to learn from experts how to migrate their existing Drupal, WordPress, or other institutional CMS to a headless architecture, or, how to start fresh and create their organization&amp;#8217;s next site using the latest technology has to offer.
            </description>
            <keywords>Mini-Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/off-with-their-heads/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="02:00 pm" end-time="02:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Matt Leahy and Shannon Leahy</speakers>
            <title>User Testing Doesn&amp;#8217;t Have to Be Hard</title>
            <description>If you&amp;#8217;re lucky, your organization has ample budget, facilities, and processes in place for robust and regular user testing. However, if you&amp;#8217;re like most of us, you&amp;#8217;re not quite so fortunate. You know it&amp;#8217;s important, but if you&amp;#8217;ve never done user research or usability testing before, it can seem like a daunting task. What do I test? Where do I find users to participate? What kind of technology do I need? Stressful!
We have good news. User testing can be simple and still produce really valuable learnings. All it takes is some creative thinking (and maybe the willingness to approach random strangers in the food court). In this session, we&amp;#8217;ll cover a variety of ways to pull off a great testing session that don&amp;#8217;t require a lot of time and resources, from paper prototypes to guerrilla usability testing to online services like usertesting.com.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/user-testing-doesnt-have-to-be-hard/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Mini-Workshop" start-time="03:00 pm" end-time="03:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Matt Gaskey</speakers>
            <title>Get More From Your Analytics By Applying an Ecommerce Model to Higher Ed &amp;#8211; Cont.</title>
            <description>Mini-Workshop: Part 2 of 2 
If you've looked at your Google Analytics dashboard, you've probably noticed a set of Ecommerce reports. If you then shrugged them off saying “We're in Higher Ed, not Ecommerce,” think again. You're missing out on a goldmine of analytics data. Learn how to apply Ecommerce tools to your higher ed site to get so much more out of Google Analytics.
Google Analytics isn't built for higher ed. That may sound harsh, but Google Analytics is, in all fairness, biased towards the Ecommerce sector. Out-of-the-box GA is sufficient to track pageviews, measure site traffic, and define goal conversions, but what about all the on-site content you work so hard to produce? Wouldn't it be useful to know what content is driving conversions?
The answer: Apply an Ecommerce approach to higher ed. Modeling your data collection as if your site were an online store will allow you to unlock the true power of Google Analytics. Want to know which pages are driving users towards goal conversions? It's as simple as assigning a value to your goals.
Just because certain aspects of Google Analytics have ‘Ecommerce' in the name doesn't mean that we can't exploit them in Higher Ed. We just have to do a bit of mental gymnastics and the plugin will bend to our collective will. Tapping into to the Ecommerce plugin means treating our business goals as products for sale. Have an event registration form? That's a product that users buy! Have a request for info? That's a product users buy!  Have an application? That's the Taj Mahal of products your users can buy!
With enhanced Ecommerce, goal conversions are no longer individual points at the end of a series, but a progression of events that can be tied to one another.
Here are just a few examples of reporting you can set up:

Product Detail to Purchase (Program Page view to Application Submission)
Product List to Purchase (Majors/Minors list to Application Submission)
Cart to Purchase (Application Starts to Application Submission)
Promotions (Special Event Views)

Not only do we gain a set of valuable reports, but we can also add multiple layers of data into every conversion on the site.
Don't ignore the Ecommerce tools in Google Analytics. Learn how to harness them.
            </description>
            <keywords>Mini-Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/get-more-from-your-analytics-by-applying-an-ecommerce-model-to-higher-ed-2/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Discussion" start-time="03:00 pm" end-time="03:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Zack Bryant</speakers>
            <title>Moral Design: Beyond Ethical Frameworks</title>
            <description>Public institutions have a unique obligation to be moral, but we&amp;#8217;re losing trust (and for good reason!). When we decline to be honest about our work, we reduce our ability to be taken seriously. Creative director, culture critic, and moderator Zack Bryant goes beyond buzzwords to unpack a moral design framework that attempts to be honest about intentions, production, limitations, and outcomes. No holds barred as we delve into dark patterns in UX/UI, the political side of stakeholder management, and the growing skepticism of social networks and data security.
            </description>
            <keywords>Discussion</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/moral-design-beyond-ethical-frameworks/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Mini-Workshop" start-time="03:00 pm" end-time="03:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Andrew Boyd and Justin Schroeder</speakers>
            <title>Off with their heads!</title>
            <description>Part 2 of 2
It&amp;#8217;s time to decapitate your CMS and go headless. The benefits of decoupling a site&amp;#8217;s presentation (or &amp;#8220;head&amp;#8221;) from its content management are dramatic: faster load times, cleaner content types, better security, and the opportunity to create stunning user interfaces. While more and more organizations want to condemn their CMS to the guillotine, they&amp;#8217;re often unsure of how to begin.
In this hands-on mini-workshop, we&amp;#8217;ll discuss the benefits of a headless architecture, review a showcase of great live headless sites, and crack open our laptops and sharpen our blades for surgery. Attendees will have the opportunity to learn from experts how to migrate their existing Drupal, WordPress, or other institutional CMS to a headless architecture, or, how to start fresh and create their organization&amp;#8217;s next site using the latest technology has to offer.
            </description>
            <keywords>Mini-Workshop</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/off-with-their-heads-2/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Discussion" start-time="03:00 pm" end-time="03:45 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Carolyn Maguire</speakers>
            <title>The Knowledge Quest (The 10 Best)</title>
            <description>Come and share your expertise. This Public Square discussion will cover how designers and developers stay current with all the changes and updates to the web development process.
In 2017 and 2018, the web development world has adopted:

new accessibility guidelines
full browser implementation of CSS Grid
updates from the CSS working group
new JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks

            </description>
            <keywords>Discussion</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/the-knowledge-quest/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="03:45 pm" end-time="04:15 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>Exhibitor Meet &amp;#038; Greet</title>
            <description>Take advantage of this extended break to visit our exhibitors.
            </description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/exhibitor-meet-greet/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="04:15 pm" end-time="05:15 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Katrina Wehr and Michael Collins</speakers>
            <title>&amp;#8220;Schema&amp;#8221; Your Way to Usable OER for Authors, Instructors, and Learners</title>
            <description>Open Educational Resources (OER) is one of the popular buzz-phrases in academia today. Many grants, initiatives, and incentives exist at universities around the country to produce and utilize OER, but what many have found is that these resources are difficult to find, difficult to access if you're outside the institution, and difficult to remix to fit your own needs. This session aims to provide the missing piece that could take OER from “lofty goal” to “practical reality” – a schema.
At Penn State, we've spent almost three years working on a pedagogy-first schema that aims to unlock OER for reuse and remix. We will discuss how attendees can utilize the schema themselves, or help OER authors at their institution use it, and become involved in the project. The session will begin with an overview of OER and barriers to implementation, the semantic web movement, and how concepts from the semantic web lead to the development of OER Schema and the OER-related challenges a schema can solve.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/schema-your-way-oer/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="04:15 pm" end-time="05:15 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Kaleem Khan</speakers>
            <title>The Futures We Want: New Horizons</title>
            <description>We are in the midst of fundamental systemic changes to our society, culture, and civilization.
The signals are all around us: algorithms, artificial intelligence, data, sensors, autonomous robots, and ubiquitous, immersive computing.
These rapidly advancing fields are already woven into the fabric of our daily lives, from how we work, learn, live, and play, to government systems, education, and justice. The challenges they pose to designers and educators present new opportunities, risks, and dangers.
Drawing upon the wisdom and warnings of Buckminster Fuller, Victor Papanek, Neil Postman, Mark Weiser, Marshall McLuhan, Al Jazari the Father of Robotics, and others, this session encourages and provokes us to question our fundamental approach to our work.
We will reflect upon the ideas, values and ethics that underpin the systems that we design, and the real and potential impact of our work as we forge our paths into new domains.
We face a choice: Will the future happen to us or will we create the futures we want?
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/the-futures-we-want-new-horizons/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="04:15 pm" end-time="05:15 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Kim Vassiliadis</speakers>
            <title>Building Accessibility into your Digital Landscape</title>
            <description>What happens when your campus finally realizes that digital accessibility is not a nice-to-have but a need-to-have requirement for your university's web presence? How do you build accessibility into your web development workflow? How do you ensure that your existing web presence is accessible? What if it&amp;#8217;s not? What if thousands of websites need to be examined? What if your university is decentralized with multiple IT groups managing various department/school websites? How do you remediate? How do you educate your community of users that accessibility is part of usability and is important? Does any of this scare you? Are you in a similar situation? We at UNC-Chapel Hill are tackling these issues now. Come and learn how we are addressing accessibility on our campus to ensure that our digital landscape is accessible for all.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/accessibility-digital-landscape/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="04:15 pm" end-time="05:15 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers>Edward Luca and Josh Boyer</speakers>
            <title>Signage by Design (In Two Hemispheres)</title>
            <description>Hear how two university libraries on opposite sides of the globe—in Sydney and Raleigh—are redesigning their signage.
Signs in libraries are one of the oldest, most ubiquitous, and important types of user interfaces. Bad signage creates visual noise and confusion and increases library anxiety. Good signage welcomes, instructs, delights, and creates a sense of belonging.
Edward Luca will show how the library at the University of Technology Sydney took a design-thinking approach to their signs to improve the library user experience, creating a delightful and functional atmosphere.
Josh Boyer will show how his team at North Carolina State University (NCSU) Libraries created touchscreen signs for the Hunt Library. They planned to add touchscreens to one other library at NCSU and consider the project done. Then, they read “Signage by Design,” an article in Weave by Edward and his colleague, Bhuva Narayan. Inspired by the Australians, NCSU team launched a more ambitious plan.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/signage-by-design/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="06:30 pm" end-time="09:30 pm">
            <location />
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>Tuesday Outings</title>
            <description></description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/tuesday-outings/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
    </day>
    <day date="2018-10-10">
        <event type="Panel" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Emily Patterson and Melanie Seibert and Shayna Diamond</speakers>
            <title>It's Not My Fault! Avoiding the Blame Game in Interdepartmental Collaboration</title>
            <description>Collaborating across departments lets us build amazing products—but it also comes with challenges. The very differences that strengthen our teams also threaten to undo our projects. Aside from scheduling conflicts, personality clashes, and differences in vision, team members typically have vastly different perspectives, vocabulary, and even goals. In this panel discussion, three professionals (a content strategist, a digital marketing specialist, and a website developer) discuss the skills and strategies they have learned to ease the stress of collaboration and make the project lifecycle productive and positive for all involved.
            </description>
            <keywords>Panel</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/blame-game/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Michael Szul</speakers>
            <title>WebAssembly: The Future of Front-End is Whatever You Want it to Be</title>
            <description>JavaScript have you down? Transpilers giving you trouble? Let me introduce WebAssembly: a safe, open, and high-performance new browser technology that allows you to easily compile some of your favorite languages to a specialized bytecode that can interact with native JavaScript and run right in the browser. Imagine writing front-end code using the same language as your back-end technology stack. This talk with give an introduction to WebAssembly, what it can do, and why it's important to the future of the web. Examples will be given in JavaScript, C, Rust, and C# (using the experimental Blazor project). With WebAssembly, the future of front-end is whatever you want it to be.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/webassembly/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Christine Tobias and Kelly Sattler</speakers>
            <title>Feeding the Animals at Our Zoo: Implementing a Bento Box Display to Improve the Search Experience</title>
            <description>Although discovery layers are intended to make it easier to find library resources, users still have difficulty interpreting search results. To alleviate confusion, a bento box design (based on the compartmentalization found in the traditional Japanese lunch) was proposed. Initial efforts to launch a bento box search result display at the MSU Libraries received opposition. User Experience and Web Services collaborated on an implementation plan that would address concerns and minimize disruption to users. Summon statistics and Google Analytics were analyzed to understand users' interactions with the discovery layer. Findings translated into design decisions for the proposed bento box display. Each branch library was also encouraged to create a similar search experience tailored for their end users. This talk summarizes this innovative process, highlighting the creativity, research, and strategy involved in implementing a bento box for a discovery layer.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/feeding-the-animals-at-our-zoo-implementing-a-bento-box-display-to-improve-the-search-experience/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="09:00 am" end-time="10:00 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Amy Deschenes</speakers>
            <title>Including People with Disabilities in User Testing</title>
            <description>Go beyond WCAG 2.0 and ensure your site is usable for people with disabilities by including them in user testing. WCAG 2.0 guidelines are an excellent tool for evaluating the accessibility of your website, but the only way to actually tell if your site is usable by people with disabilities is to include them in your user testing. At Harvard, we've built a participant pool of native assistive technology users who can be hired by staff to test digital products for accessibility. In our testing, we've learned things that an automated accessibility testing tool would miss and improved our website experience for all users, no matter how they access the web.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/disabilities-in-user-testing/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Ann Shivers-McNair and Rebecca Blakiston</speakers>
            <title>Do No Harm: Making Better Forms for People</title>
            <description>In higher education, forms are everywhere. Students use them to register for classes, staff use them to get technical help, and faculty use them to request classroom spaces and technology. But too often, we don't give these forms the care and nurturing they deserve. In this session, attendees will learn how to empathize with users in order to design and write forms that are better for the people who have to use them. Attendees will learn how to ensure their forms are inclusive, approachable, and human-centered. We will cover a range of considerations from format, plain language, and structure to details like confirmation messages, button placement, and field labels. By the end of this session, attendees will be able to create forms that have users saying, “that's nice!” and not, “this sucks!”
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/do-no-harm/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>JoAnna Dettmann and Kaysha Hanock</speakers>
            <title>How Voice Search Is Impacting Your Business—And What to Do About It</title>
            <description>Voice search has been gaining popularity ever since Siri found her way into consumers' iPhones—and hearts—over five years ago. Now, with the ubiquity of virtual assistants like Amazon's Alexa and Microsoft's Cortana, and improvements in technology, the uptick in voice search queries is increasing exponentially. Google estimated 20% of mobile queries were voice searches in 2016, and Comscore estimates 50% of all searches will come from voice commands by 2020.
This exponential growth cannot be ignored. Because consumers use voice search differently than typed search, web presence optimization must be conducted with a different mindset. Especially for organizations that rely on local search traffic, this has important ramifications for their strategy. So, how can you ensure that your business isn't left behind when half the population is searching for you through a virtual assistant? From optimizing microdata to utilizing long-tail keywords, it all begins with SEO.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/voice-search/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>John Rhea</speakers>
            <title>Once Upon a Time: Using Story Structure for Better Engagement</title>
            <description>&amp;#8220;Let me tell you a story.&amp;#8221;
From campfires to books to advertisements to film, stories have a power over us that no other human invention can wield. They calm us, thrill us, enthrall us, and send us running back to the box office for another hit.
But there&amp;#8217;s no real secret to the multi-billion-dollar &amp;#8220;secret&amp;#8221; sauce behind Hollywood and the entertainment industry. Stories have structure and common elements, and they can be applied to almost anything, increasing both engagement and user understanding. You, too, can wrap your website content in a story that makes candy out of a bitter pill.
It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter if you sell paper to accountants or slick technology to the in-crowd. Invite your users into a story larger than themselves, and you&amp;#8217;ll have them loving your work and shouting for more.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/once-upon-a-time/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Talk" start-time="10:15 am" end-time="11:15 am">
            <location />
            <speakers>Kevin Pittman</speakers>
            <title>Making JavaScript Powered UI Accessible</title>
            <description>Site designers love tab panels, accordion sets, slideshows, and hover-drop-down menu bars—anything to squeeze more content into less space. Unfortunately, many out-of-the box tools to generate these components can be severely lacking in accessibility compliance. At some point, you may wish to just craft your own accessibility compliant components, but how do you do that?
Using WebAIM&amp;#8217;s tutorials as a reference, we&amp;#8217;ll dive into how to build the JavaScript needed to power these important UI tools while keeping the user experience fully accessible. Lots of code samples will be provided with clear explanation of how they work. The examples are based on using Drupal with the Paragraphs module as your website base, but the concepts can be applied to many other kinds of content systems.
            </description>
            <keywords>Talk</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/javascript-ui-accessible/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="Keynote" start-time="11:30 am" end-time="12:30 pm">
            <location>Jefferson Theater</location>
            <speakers>Baratunde Thurston</speakers>
            <title>Digital Storytelling Doesn't Have To Be Boring And Sucky. It Can Be Fun!</title>
            <description>There's just too much content in the world, and getting people's attention is, like life, hard.
Baratunde Thurston was a political blogger for four years, ran digital strategy for The Onion for five years, authored a New York Times best-selling book How To Be Black that continues to find life on Instagram, and lives to engage communities and tell stories in fun and empathetic ways.
This talk comes with guaranteed laughs and guaranteed actionable insights based on Baratunde's direct experience, the work of his media company Cultivated Wit, and the good work of people with whom he has no connection but for whom he has respect because he's humble like that.
            </description>
            <keywords>Keynote</keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/digital-storytelling/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
        <event type="" start-time="12:30 pm" end-time="01:00 pm">
            <location>Jefferson Theater</location>
            <speakers></speakers>
            <title>10th Annual edUi Celebration</title>
            <description>Join us as we celebrate our 10th annual conference. There will be cake!
            </description>
            <keywords></keywords>
            <link>https://www.eduiconf.org/schedule/10th-annual-edui-celebration/</link>
            <photos />
        </event>
    </day>
</conference>
